<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<action-plan format="Audio/Video Interleaved Format">
  <confidence-level>High: AVI uncompressed motion JPEG, Low: AVI (others)</confidence-level>
  <implementation-date>2005.09.06</implementation-date>
  <revision-date>2012.08.01</revision-date>
  <review-date>2008.01.07</review-date>
  <next-review>2012.01</next-review>
  <ingest-processing>
    <identification>
      Yes
    </identification>
    <validation>
      Yes
    </validation>
    <characterization>
      Yes
    </characterization>
    <migration>
      No
    </migration>
    <normalization>
      Yes
	  <VideoStreams>
	    Each supported video stream contained in an AVI file will be normalized into a motion JPEG video 
	    stream which contains a sequence of JPEG images.  The normalized motion JPEG video stream will 
	    have the same video dimension and playback rate(frames/second) as the original stream.  
        <stream>
           <format>CinePak</format>
           <code>CVID</code>
           <normalized-stream>Motion JPEG</normalized-stream>
        </stream>
       <stream>
           <format>Motion JPEG</format>
           <code>MJPG</code>
           <normalized-stream>Not Applicable</normalized-stream>
        </stream>
       <stream>
           <format>Indeo 3.2</format>
           <code>IV32</code>
           <normalized-stream>Motion JPEG</normalized-stream>
        </stream>
      </VideoStreams>
	  <AudioStreams>
	    Each audio stream in the AVI file will be normalized into an uncompressed PCM (LPCM) audio stream 
	    with sample size of 16 bits/sample.  The normalized audio stream will have the same sample rate 
	    (samples/second) as the original one.
	    The normalized video streams and audio streams will be multiplexed back into an AVI file.
	    <stream>
           <format>WAVE LPCM</format>
           <code>0x0001</code>
           <normalized-stream>Not Applicable</normalized-stream>
        </stream>
	  </AudioStreams>
      <transformation id="avi_norm"/>	
    </normalization>
  </ingest-processing>
  <significant-properties>
    <content>
      TBD
    </content>
    <context>
      TBD
    </context>
    <behavior>TBD
    </behavior>
    <structure>
      TBD
    </structure>
    <appearance>
      TBD
    </appearance>
  </significant-properties>

  <long-term-strategy>
    <original>
      Migrate to newer AVI versions or to an open, standardized and well supported multimedia file
      format that is to be a good successor for the AVI file format.

      No normalized version will be created for AVI 1.0 files. However, each video/audio stream
      contained in the AVI file will be normalized according to the normalization section  
      in the ingest processing. If the encoded video/audio stream is not in the list of 
      supported video/audio stream formats for AVI file format, the video/audio stream will not be
      normalized and it will be preserved as bit-level.
    </original>

    <normalized>
      Not applicable for AVI 1.0 file format. 
      <normalized-video>Migrate to an open, standardized and well supported video stream format that does not use interframes  (temporal compression). </normalized-video> 
      <normalized-audio>Migrate to an open, standardized and well supported audio stream format that is losslessly compressed.</normalized-audio>
    </normalized>
  </long-term-strategy>

  <short-term-actions>
    <action>
      None
    </action>
  </short-term-actions>
  <footnote>
    This action plan is currently under discussion and is subject to change.
  </footnote>
</action-plan>

