<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<action-plan format="BIFF8">
	<implementation-date>TBD</implementation-date>
	<release-date>2003-05-08</release-date>
	<revision-date>2010-04</revision-date>
	<ingest-processing>
		<identification>
			Yes, BIFF8 files will be identified using magic number, which is described 
			in section 1.14 of BIFF8 Action Plan Background. 
		</identification>
		<validation>
			Yes, the validation of BIFF8 files will be performed according to the 
			specification requirements in section 1.15 of BIFF8 Action Plan Background.
		</validation>
		<characterization>
			Yes, please refers to section 2.1 of BIFF8 Action Plan Background for the list of BIFF8 technical metadata extracted. 
		</characterization>
		<migration>
			Yes, BIFF8 files will be migrated to OOXML spreadsheet format.
			<transformation url="http://localhost:7000/transformation/transform/biff8_mig"/>
		</migration>
		<normalization>
			Yes, BIFF8 files will be normalized to Open Document Spreadsheet (ODF) 
			via migrations to OOXML spreadsheet. 					
			<transformation url="http://localhost:7000/transformation/transform/biff8_norm"/>
		</normalization>
	</ingest-processing>
	<significant-properties>
		<content>
			All cell data and formula will be preserved.  Chart and Pivot tables may not be 
			preserved. 
		</content>
		<context>
			Context: Contextual information about the spreadsheet, such as author, title, etc, will be 
			preserved.
		</context> 
		<behavior>BIFF8 can encode VBA macros which can be used for defining custom 
			spreadsheet behaviors.  In addition, BIFF8 can contain external links to external sources. 
			These behaviors may not be preserved.
		</behavior>
		<structure>
			Structural information such as the cell locations (row, column) and the nested 
			worksheets will be preserved. 
		</structure>
		<appearance>
			BIFF8 can contain appearance attributes such as fonts, colors, sizes, cell 
			formats, etc.  Cell formats will be preserved. The rest of the appearance attributes may not 
			be preserved
		</appearance>
	</significant-properties>
	<long-term-strategy>
		<original>
			Migrate to OOXML spreadsheet format which supersedes BIFF8 format.  The OOXML 
			spreadsheet format shares the same essential and distinguishing characteristics with BIFF8. 
		</original>
		<normalized>
			The migrated version will be normalized to Open Document Spreadsheet (ODS) format.  Please 
			refer to the action plan for OOXML spreadsheet format once OOXML spreadsheet format 
			becomes supported by Florida Digital Archive. 
		</normalized>
	</long-term-strategy>
	<short-term-actions>
		<action>
			Evaluate the possibility of supporting the OOXML spreadsheet format in the Florida Digital 
			Archive.  Please note the draft specification for OOXML (DIS 29500) may be changed during 
			the ISO standardization process. 
		</action>
		<action>
			Evaluate the conversion to OOXML spreadsheets when Office Binary Translators to XML is 
			available for spreadsheets (after summer 2008). 
		</action>
		<action>
			Find and investigate suitable conversion software for converting OOXML spreadsheet to ODS.  
			One of the possible tool is Open XML/ODF Translator command line software. 
		</action>
	</short-term-actions>
	<note>
		This action plan is currently (03/4/08) under discussion and is subject to change.
	</note>
</action-plan>
