<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<action-plan format="ASCII">
  <confidence-level>High: encoding: US-ASCII, UTF-8, UTF-16 with BOM; delimited text, Medium: ISO 885901 encoding</confidence-level>
  <implementation-date>2003.03.19</implementation-date>
  <revision-date>2012.07.22</revision-date>
  <review-date>2007.08.24</review-date>
  <next-review>2012.08</next-review>
  <ingest-processing>
    <identification>
      Yes, by parsing the entire file or the first 65536 characters for large files.
      Plain Text can only contain octets with hexadecimal value in the range of [0x07, 0x0d],
      [0x20, 0x7e], [0x80, 0xfe], and 0x1b.
    </identification>
    <validation>
      Yes. Same rules as identification.
    </validation>
    <characterization>
      Yes. Extracted format metadata are described in Section 2.1 of Plain
      Text Action Plan Background.
    </characterization>
    <migration>
      No
    </migration>
    <normalization>
      No
    </normalization>
  </ingest-processing>
  <significant-properties>
	Plain text exhibits the following significant properties (note 1). It is intended to preserve and evaluate
	these significant properties when adopting migration or normalization policy in the future.
    <content>
      All content, including every character, will be preserved.
    </content>
    <context>
      N/A. Plain Text does not contain metadata to describe the environment where it
      was originally created or used.
    </context>
    <behavior>
      N/A. Plain Text does not provide interactive characteristics.
    </behavior>
    <structure>
      The location of every linebreak will be preserved. There is no other predefined
      structure for Plain Text.
    </structure>
    <appearance>
      N/A. Plain Text does not store appearance attributes such as font (including
      font size or font style), color, alignment, etc.
    </appearance>
  </significant-properties>

  <long-term-strategy>
    <original>
      Plain text files will be preserved “as is”.
    </original>

    <normalized>
      Not applicable
    </normalized>
  </long-term-strategy>

  <short-term-actions>
    <action>
      No actions
    </action>
  </short-term-actions>
  <note>
    1. “From digital volatility to digital permanence, Preserving text documents”, Jacqueline Slats, The Hague,
    November 2003, http://www.digitaleduurzaamheid.nl/bibliotheek/docs/volatility-permanence-textdocs-en.pdf
  </note>
  <footnote>
    This action plan is currently under discussion and is subject to change.
  </footnote>
</action-plan>

