<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<action-plan format="Quicktime">
  <confidence-level>High: uncompressed motion JPEG, Low: others</confidence-level>
  <implementation-date>2006.01.24</implementation-date>
  <revision-date>2012.08.01</revision-date>
  <review-date>2008.01.07</review-date>
  <next-review>2012.01</next-review>
  <ingest-processing>
    <identification>
      Yes
    </identification>
    <validation>
      Yes
    </validation>
    <characterization>
      Yes
    </characterization>
    <migration>
      No
    </migration>
    <normalization>
      Yes
      <VideoStreams>
	  Each supported video stream contained in a QuickTime movie file will be normalized into a motion 
	  JPEG-A video stream which contains a sequence of JPEG images.  The normalized motion JPEG-A video 
	  stream will have the same video dimension and playback rate as the original video stream.  
      <stream>
          <format>CinePak</format>
          <code>CVID</code>
          <normalized-stream>Motion JPEG (MJPA)</normalized-stream>
       </stream>
       <stream>
          <format>Motion JPEG</format>
          <code>MJPA</code>
          <normalized-stream>Not Applicable</normalized-stream>
       </stream>
       <stream>
          <format>Graphics</format>
          <code>SMC</code>
          <normalized-stream>Motion JPEG (MJPA)</normalized-stream>
       </stream>
       <stream>
          <format>Advanced Video Coding</format>
          <code>AVC1</code>
          <normalized-stream>Motion JPEG (MJPA)</normalized-stream>
       </stream>
      </VideoStreams>
	  <AudioStreams>
	    Each audio stream in a QuickTime movie file will be normalized 
	    into an uncompressed audio stream with the same sample size and sample rate.
	    The normalized video and audio streams will be multiplexed back into a QuickTime movie file.
	    <stream>
           <format>Uncompressed</format>
           <code>NONE</code>
           <normalized-stream>Not Applicable</normalized-stream>
        </stream>
	  </AudioStreams>	
      <transformation id="mov_norm"/>
    </normalization>
  </ingest-processing>
  <significant-properties>
    <content>
      TBD
    </content>
    <context>
      TBD
    </context>
    <behavior>TBD
    </behavior>
    <structure>
      TBD
    </structure>
    <appearance>
      TBD
    </appearance>
  </significant-properties>

  <long-term-strategy>
    <original>
      Migrate to an open, standardized and well supported multimedia file format that is to be a good 
      successor for the QuickTime file format.

      No normalized version will be created for QuickTime movie files. However, each video/audio
      stream contained in a QuickTime file will be normalized according to the normalization section  
      in the ingest processing. If the encoded video/audio stream is not in the list of
      supported video/audio stream formats for QuickTime movie file, the video/audio stream
      will not be normalized and it will be preserved as bit-level.
    </original>

    <normalized>
      Not applicable for QuckTime file format. For the normalized video and audio stream formats,
      please see the Action Plan for FDA Supported Video/Audio Stream Formats.
      <normalized-video>Migrate to an open, standardized and well supported video encoding format that does not use interframes  (temporal compression). </normalized-video> 
      <normalized-audio>Migrate to an open, standardized and well supported audio stream format that is losslessly compressed.</normalized-audio>
    </normalized>
  </long-term-strategy>

  <short-term-actions>
    <action>
      None
    </action>
  </short-term-actions>
  <footnote>
    This action plan is currently under discussion and is subject to change.
  </footnote>
</action-plan>

