<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- Change History

07-24-2003
Deleted all descriptions of the algorithm used to resolve file
references, instead referring to a separate FDA report (“Resolving
References in Distributed Objects”) for the details.

02-01-2008
Added Ingest Processing and Significant Properties sections.

-->

<action-plan format="Extensible Markup Language" format-version="1.0">
  <implementation-date>2003-06-09</implementation-date>
  <review-date>2008-02-01</review-date>
  <next-review>2011-02</next-review>
  <ingest-processing>
    <identification>
      Yes, only documents conforming to the well-formedness rules defined by
      the XML 1.0 specification will be identified as XML.
    </identification>
    <validation>
      Yes. The FDA uses the validation rules specified in the XML 1.0 specification.
    </validation>
    <characterization>
      Yes. Extracted technical metadata are described in section 2.2 of XML
      action plan background.
    </characterization>
    <localization>
      Yes. A localized version will be created for an XML file if it
      contains at least one named reference to an external schema and
      the reference can be resolved to a physical file using the
      process described in “Resolving References in Distributed
      Objects”, available on the Florida Digital Archive(FDA)
      website. The format for this version, 'XML_norm_1', is described
      in a separate FDA publication (“A Specification of the
      XML_NORM_1 Format”).
    </localization>
    <migration>
      No
    </migration>
    <normalization>
      No
    </normalization>
    <xmlresolution>
      http://localhost:7000/xmlresolution
    </xmlresolution>
  </ingest-processing>
  <significant-properties>
    <content>
      All textual content will be preserved. Data defined inside &lt;CDATA&gt; will be
      preserved as is.
    </content>
    <context>
      Yes. Contextual information described in XML documents will be preserved.
    </context>
    <behavior>
      External schema referenced by XML documents will be preserved. The
      validation status of the XML documents will be preserved. XML behaviors defined in
      &lt;CDATA&gt; section, such as java script, may not be preserved.
    </behavior>
    <structure>
      Yes. The tree-like element structure defined in XML documents will be
      preserved.
    </structure>
    <appearance>
      N/A. XML does not contain appearance attributes. However, XML
      documents can be associated with XML style sheets to define their appearance. The
      preservation of XML style sheet is out of the scope of this document.
    </appearance>
  </significant-properties>

  <long-term-strategy>
    <original>
      Migrate to XML 1.1 when XML 1.1 is supported by the FDA.
    </original>
    <localized>
      Same as the original.
    </localized>
  </long-term-strategy>

  <short-term-actions>
    <action>
      N/A
    </action>
  </short-term-actions>
  <note>
    This action plan is currently (02/01/08) under discussion and is subject to change.
  </note>
</action-plan>
