<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Change History:

01-30-2008
Added Ingest Processing and Significant Properties sections.

-->
<action-plan format="XMLDTD" format-version="1.0">
  <implementation-date>2003-07-22</implementation-date>
  <review-date>2008-02-01</review-date>
  <next-review>2011-02</next-review>
  <ingest-processing>
    <identification>
      Yes, only markup declaration conforming to the plain text identification
      rules and the well-formedness rules defined in the XML 1.0 specification are identified as DTD.
    </identification>
    <validation>
      Yes. DTD must conform to the validation rules specified in the XML 1.0
      specification.
    </validation>
    <characterization>
      Yes. Extracted technical metadata are described in section 2.2 of XML
      DTD action plan background.
    </characterization>
    <localization>
        Yes.  A localized version will be created for a DTD file if it
        contains at least one named reference to an external file (a
        'link'), and the reference can be resolved to a physical file
        using the resolution algorithms described in “Resolving
        References in Distributed Objects” report, available on the
        Florida Digital Archive (FDA) website. The format of this
        version, XML_DTD_NORM_1, are described in a separate FDA
        report (“A Specification of the XML_DTD_NORM_1 Format”)
        available on the FDA website.
    </localization>
    <migration>
      No
    </migration>
    <normalization>
      No
    </normalization>
  </ingest-processing>
  <significant-properties>
    <content>
      All textual content will be preserved.
    </content>
    <context>
      N/A. DTD may contain definitions for storing contextual information. It does
      not contain the actual context.
    </context>
    <behavior>  Constraints defined in DTD files will be preserved.
    </behavior>
    <structure>
      Document structures defined in DTD files will be preserved.
    </structure>
    <appearance>
      N/A. DTD does not provide a way to specify how DTD documents may be
      displayed.
    </appearance>
  </significant-properties>
  <long-term-strategy>
    <original>
      Migrate to a newer version of XML DTD or to a different XML schema language when the
      XML DTD 1.0 format becomes unsupported by XML readers.
    </original>
    <localized>
      Same as the original (see 3.1).
    </localized>
    <normalized>
      N/A
    </normalized>
  </long-term-strategy>

  <short-term-actions>
    <action>
      N/A
    </action>
  </short-term-actions>
  <note>
    This action plan is currently (02/01/08) under discussion and is subject to change.
  </note>
</action-plan>

